Selling on Amazon can be broken down into four steps.
Step 1.
Create an Amazon Seller Central account on sell.
amazon.
com.
Step 2.
List Products for Sale.
Step 3.
Fulfill Customer Orders and Provide Outstanding Customer Service.
Step 4.
Receive payments from your sales proceeds and maintain your account health.
Let's go over these four steps.
Step 1.
Create an Amazon Seller Central Account.
Before you register for an account with Amazon,
choose between professional or individual selling plan.
Confused on which plan is right for your business?
There are a few important differences.
Between the two plans.
Let's compare.
Professional accounts
carry a flat monthly subscription fee of $39.99 no matter how many items you sell.
This type
of account makes sense if you're planning to sell a lot of items.
An individual account
is a better choice if you only plan to make a few sales each month.
Instead of a flat
monthly subscription fee, you pay a per item fee of $0.99 for every item you sell.
Both
individual and professional seller accounts are eligible for FBA service.
Now let's take
a look at the features which are only available for professional selling account.
Customized
shipping rates.
Bulk listing tools.
Advertising, deals and coupons.
Automated pricing tools.
Amazon Selling Coach.
Marketplace web services and much more.
Now let's look at Step 2.
List
products.
You can list a product to sell on Amazon in less than five minutes.
Here's how.
Amazon's product listing allows sellers to match an existing listing.
If someone is already
selling the same product or create a new listing if you are the first or only seller.
If you
are reselling products already present in Amazon's catalog, this can be a fast way to add selection
to your account.
What if my selection doesn't match the existing offers?
If you are selling
your own brand, private label, or bringing new product selections to a category, you'll
want to create a new detail page on Amazon.
To create a new listing, you will need a product
identifier, also known as a barcode.
Commonly used identifier terms include UPC, GTIN, EAN
or ISBN.
Not exactly sure what a barcode is.
Look for barcodes on some of your favorite
items or watch what a clerk scans to get a price in a store.
Look at the numbers printed
below the barcode.
A 12-digit number is a UPC or a 13-digit number is an EAN.
If the
products you intend to sell do not have a barcode.
Apply for a GTIN exemption.
You can
then add the selection without the need for barcode numbers.
Add listings to your account,
one by one using the add a product option.
Add bulk inventory all at once by using the
add products via upload option.
Special listing options cater to the unique demands
of handmade and customizable listing sellers.
Step three, fulfill orders and provide outstanding
customer service.
Now that your product listings are complete, choose how to best fulfill orders.
The FBA program gives sellers the opportunity to use Amazon's world-class shipping, logistics
and customer service partnerships to benefit their buyers.
Sellers using FBA send their
products to Amazon's fulfillment centers.
We take care of packaging, shipping, returns
and customer service issues.
Products are prime enabled with a prime badge logo.
Sellers
that prefer to do their own or merchant fulfilled shipping are responsible for packages being
shipped and delivered on time, customer service and returns.
Step four, receive payments from
your sales proceeds.
Amazon pays you through an automatic clearing house payment to your
bank account every two weeks on eligible sales proceeds.
To determine sales proceeds and
profitability, sellers should become familiar with Amazon's fee schedule.
On your Seller
Central home page, type in selling on Amazon fee schedule in the search bar.
This will direct
you to the help page.
The help page lists all fees related to selling on Amazon.
Lastly,
we recommend you to visit account health under the performance tab on seller central to regularly
monitor your performance as a seller.
This wraps up how selling on Amazon works.
Thank
you, and happy selling!